<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>The standard of the Lord lifted up in New-England, in opposition to the man of sin, or, The trumpet of the Lord sounding there with a visitation to the suffering seed of God in New-England or elsewhere with a warning from the Lord to the rulers and magistrates, priests, and people of New-England, but more especially to the rulers and magistrates of the bloody town of Boston, who have put the servants of the living God to death / written (in the prison at Boston in New-England in America) by ... Joseph Nicholson.</title>
            <author>Nicholson, Joseph, 17th cent.</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <editionStmt>
            <edition>
               <date>1660</date>
            </edition>
         </editionStmt>
         <extent>Approx. 50 KB of XML-encoded text transcribed from 13 1-bit group-IV TIFF page images.</extent>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>Text Creation Partnership,</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Ann Arbor, MI ; Oxford (UK) :</pubPlace>
            <date when="2011-12">2011-12 (EEBO-TCP Phase 2).</date>
            <idno type="DLPS">A52300</idno>
            <idno type="STC">Wing N1109</idno>
            <idno type="STC">ESTC R4235</idno>
            <idno type="EEBO-CITATION">12413944</idno>
            <idno type="OCLC">ocm 12413944</idno>
            <idno type="VID">61620</idno>
            <availability>
               <p>To the extent possible under law, the Text Creation Partnership has waived all copyright and related or neighboring rights to this keyboarded and encoded edition of the work described above, according to the terms of the CC0 1.0 Public Domain Dedication (http://creativecommons.org/publicdomain/zero/1.0/). This waiver does not extend to any page images or other supplementary files associated with this work, which may be protected by copyright or other license restrictions. Please go to https://www.textcreationpartnership.org/ for more information about the project.</p>
            </availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <seriesStmt>
            <title>Early English books online.</title>
         </seriesStmt>
         <notesStmt>
            <note>(EEBO-TCP ; phase 2, no. A52300)</note>
            <note>Transcribed from: (Early English Books Online ; image set 61620)</note>
            <note>Images scanned from microfilm: (Early English books, 1641-1700 ; 284:17)</note>
         </notesStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <biblFull>
               <titleStmt>
                  <title>The standard of the Lord lifted up in New-England, in opposition to the man of sin, or, The trumpet of the Lord sounding there with a visitation to the suffering seed of God in New-England or elsewhere with a warning from the Lord to the rulers and magistrates, priests, and people of New-England, but more especially to the rulers and magistrates of the bloody town of Boston, who have put the servants of the living God to death / written (in the prison at Boston in New-England in America) by ... Joseph Nicholson.</title>
                  <author>Nicholson, Joseph, 17th cent.</author>
               </titleStmt>
               <extent>24 p.   </extent>
               <publicationStmt>
                  <publisher>Printed for Robert Wilson ...,</publisher>
                  <pubPlace>London :</pubPlace>
                  <date>1660.</date>
               </publicationStmt>
               <notesStmt>
                  <note>On the persecution of the Quakers.</note>
                  <note>Reproduction of original in University of Michigan Libraries.</note>
               </notesStmt>
            </biblFull>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <projectDesc>
            <p>Created by converting TCP files to TEI P5 using tcp2tei.xsl,
      TEI @ Oxford.
      </p>
         </projectDesc>
         <editorialDecl>
            <p>EEBO-TCP is a partnership between the Universities of Michigan and Oxford and the publisher ProQuest to create accurately transcribed and encoded texts based on the image sets published by ProQuest via their Early English Books Online (EEBO) database (http://eebo.chadwyck.com). The general aim of EEBO-TCP is to encode one copy (usually the first edition) of every monographic English-language title published between 1473 and 1700 available in EEBO.</p>
            <p>EEBO-TCP aimed to produce large quantities of textual data within the usual project restraints of time and funding, and therefore chose to create diplomatic transcriptions (as opposed to critical editions) with light-touch, mainly structural encoding based on the Text Encoding Initiative (http://www.tei-c.org).</p>
            <p>The EEBO-TCP project was divided into two phases. The 25,368 texts created during Phase 1 of the project (2000-2009), initially available only to institutions that contributed to their creation, were released into the public domain on 1 January 2015. The approximately 40,000 texts produced during Phase 2 (2009- ), of which 34,963 had been released as of 2020, originally similarly restricted, were similarly freed from all restrictions on 1 August 2020. As of that date anyone is free to take and use these texts for any purpose (modify them, annotate them, distribute them, etc.). But we do respectfully request that due credit and attribution be given to their original source.</p>
            <p>Users should be aware of the process of creating the TCP texts, and therefore of any assumptions that can be made about the data.</p>
            <p>Text selection was based on the New Cambridge Bibliography of English Literature (NCBEL). If an author (or for an anonymous work, the title) appears in NCBEL, then their works are eligible for inclusion. Selection was intended to range over a wide variety of subject areas, to reflect the true nature of the print record of the period. In general, first editions of a works in English were prioritized, although there are a number of works in other languages, notably Latin and Welsh, included and sometimes a second or later edition of a work was chosen if there was a compelling reason to do so.</p>
            <p>Image sets were sent to external keying companies for transcription and basic encoding. Quality assurance was then carried out by editorial teams in Oxford and Michigan. 5% (or 5 pages, whichever is the greater) of each text was proofread for accuracy and those which did not meet QA standards were returned to the keyers to be redone. After proofreading, the encoding was enhanced and/or corrected and characters marked as illegible were corrected where possible up to a limit of 100 instances per text. Any remaining illegibles were encoded as &lt;gap&gt;s. Understanding these processes should make clear that, while the overall quality of TCP data is very good, some errors will remain and some readable characters will be marked as illegible. Users should bear in mind that in all likelihood such instances will never have been looked at by a TCP editor.</p>
            <p>The texts were encoded and linked to page images in accordance with level 4 of the TEI in Libraries guidelines.</p>
            <p>Copies of the texts have been issued variously as SGML (TCP schema; ASCII text with mnemonic sdata character entities); displayable XML (TCP schema; characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or text strings within braces); or lossless XML (TEI P5, characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or TEI g elements).</p>
            <p>Keying and markup guidelines are available at the <ref target="http://www.textcreationpartnership.org/docs/.">Text Creation Partnership web site</ref>.</p>
         </editorialDecl>
         <listPrefixDef>
            <prefixDef ident="tcp"
                       matchPattern="([0-9\-]+):([0-9IVX]+)"
                       replacementPattern="http://eebo.chadwyck.com/downloadtiff?vid=$1&amp;page=$2"/>
            <prefixDef ident="char"
                       matchPattern="(.+)"
                       replacementPattern="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/textcreationpartnership/Texts/master/tcpchars.xml#$1"/>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="eng">eng</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="http://authorities.loc.gov/">
               <term>Society of Friends --  New England.</term>
               <term>Society of Friends --  Massachusetts --  Boston.</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2010-06</date>
            <label>TCP</label>Assigned for keying and markup</change>
         <change>
            <date>2010-06</date>
            <label>SPi Global</label>Keyed and coded from ProQuest page images</change>
         <change>
            <date>2010-08</date>
            <label>Pip Willcox</label>Sampled and proofread</change>
         <change>
            <date>2010-08</date>
            <label>Pip Willcox</label>Text and markup reviewed and edited</change>
         <change>
            <date>2011-06</date>
            <label>pfs</label>Batch review (QC) and XML conversion</change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text xml:lang="eng">
      <front>
         <div type="title_page">
            <pb facs="tcp:61620:1"/>
            <pb facs="tcp:61620:1"/>
            <p>THE STANDARD Of the Lord lifted up in New-England, In Oppoſition to the MAN OF SIN: OR, The Trumpet of the Lord ſounding there, with a Viſitation to the ſuffering <hi>Seed of God</hi> in <hi>New-England,</hi> or elſewhere.</p>
            <p>With a Warning from the Lord, to the Rulers and Magiſtrates, Prieſts and People of <hi>New-Eng<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>land;</hi> but more eſpecially to the Rulers and Magiſtrates of the Bloody Town of <hi>Boſton,</hi> who have put the Servants of the Living God to Death.</p>
            <q>
               <p>
                  <hi>The Lyon hath roared, who can but fear? The Trumpet hath ſound<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ed, who can but prepare himſelf to Battel, before the great and notable day of the Lord come?</hi>
               </p>
            </q>
            <q>
               <p>Fear ye not me, ſaith the Lord? will ye not tremble at my preſence, which placed the ſands for the bounds of the Sea, by a perpetual Decree, that it cannot paſſe it; and though the waves thereof toſſe themſelves, yet can they not prevail; though they roar, yet can they not paſs over it?</p>
               <bibl>
                  <hi>Jer. 5.20.</hi>
               </bibl>
            </q>
            <p>Written (in the Priſon at <hi>Boſton</hi> in
<hi>New-England,</hi> in <hi>America,</hi>) By a Friend of <hi>Iſraels</hi> Commonwealth, known to the world by name, <hi>Joſeph Nicholſon.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>
               <hi>LONDON,</hi> Printed for <hi>Robert Wilſon,</hi> at the Signe of the <hi>Black-ſpread-Eagle</hi> and <hi>Winde-mil</hi> in
<hi>Martins Le grand,</hi> 1660.</p>
         </div>
      </front>
      <body>
         <div type="tract">
            <pb facs="tcp:61620:2" rendition="simple:additions"/>
            <pb n="3" facs="tcp:61620:2"/>
            <head>The Standard of the Lord lifted up in <hi>New-England;</hi> or the Trumpet of the Lord ſound<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing there.</head>
            <p>THe mighty day of the Lord is coming, wherein the ſecrets of every mans heart ſhall be revealed with the Light of Jeſus Chriſt, which comes from Jeſus Chriſt, the Son of God, <hi>who lighteth every man that comes into the world, John</hi> 1. <hi>ver.</hi> 9. <hi>And this is my beloved Son, ſaith God, hear you him, who lighteth every man that comes into the world;</hi> Drunkard hates the Light, Lyar hates the Light, Swearers, and curſed Speakers, you all hate the Light; and all you who live by ſtealth, you hate the Light; all you that live in envy, as <hi>Cain</hi> did, who ſlew his Brother, you hate the Light; all you that are proud, as <hi>Haman</hi> was, ye hate the Light; all you who commit adultery, you hate the Light; all you who live by cozening and cheating your fellow-crea<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tures, by deceitful merchandize, in buying and ſelling, and ſpeaking otherwiſe by your commodities than it is, you hate the Light; and all you who live in any form of Profeſſion whatſoever, and perſecute them who are in the life, who come to witneſs forth the Truth, as it is in Jeſus Chriſt, made manifeſted in them, as it was in the Apoſtles, you are all to be condemned with the Light that comes from Jeſus Chriſt, <hi>For
<gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>his is the condemnation of the world,</hi> (the Light) ſaith Chriſt, <hi>
                  <gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>hat Light is come into the world, and men love darkneſs rather than light, becauſe their deeds are evil;</hi> John 3.
<hi>ver.</hi> 19. <hi>For e<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>very one that doth evil, hateth the Light, neither cometh to the <gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>ight, leſt his deeds ſhould be reproved; but he that doth truth,
<gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="2 letters">
                     <desc>••</desc>
                  </gap>meth to the Light, that his deeds may be made manifeſt, that they are wrought in God:</hi> Therefore all people, high and low, <pb n="4" facs="tcp:61620:3"/>rich and poor, bond and free, take warning betime, and put not the evil day afar off, and the good day afar off, and ſay in your hearts the Lord delayeth his coming, and ſo eat and drink with drunkards, and beat and perſecute your fellow-creatures, who witneſs the life and Power, as they did who ſpoke-forth the Scriptures, <hi>for the Scriptures was given forth by Inſpiration of the Spirit, holy men of God ſpake as they were moved by the Holy Ghoſt, and as the Spirit gave them utterance.</hi> Now people conſider, the Scripture was not given forth for men to talk of, or make a trade of, or for men to get money by, as your hireling Teachers of the world do, who have ſo much a year for preaching, and talking of the Scriptures, of things made ready to their hands, other mens conditions, ſaying in ſuch a Chapter, and ſuch a verſe, ſay<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing, Hearken my beloved brethren, in ſuch a Chapter, and ſuch a verſe, <hi>to the Word of God, as it is written for your in<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtruction,</hi> when truly people the Lord never ſpoke unto them: Why may ſome ſay, is not the Scriptures true? yea, they are true, but the Scripture as a declaration of other mens conditi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ons, the Prophets conditions, &amp; Chriſts words, &amp; the Apoſtles words given forth from the life, but I am againſt him, ſaith the Lord, <hi>that ſteals the Word from his Neighbour,</hi> and ſaith,
<hi>The Lord ſaith,</hi> when the Lord never ſpoke to him, but as they find it written in the Scriptures, other mens conditions, who were made partakers, and poſſeſſed and enjoyed what they ſpoke, this was not a Chapter, or verſe in Scripture, o<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ther mens conditions, but this was, and is the ſame as ever was from the beginning, the Innocent life, the holy life,
<hi>Adams</hi> ſtate, wherein he was created at firſt in the Image of God, but being fallen from that eſtate in <hi>Adam,</hi> there muſt be a coming back again, as the Scriptures ſpeaks of, <hi>I will bring the blind by a way that they have not known,</hi> and there muſt be a bring<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing back again the Captivity, a reſtauration out of the fallen eſtate, <hi>For as in</hi> Adam
<hi>all die, ſo in Chriſt ſhall all be made a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>live: As many as believe on him whom the Father hath ſent into the World, he was in the world, and the world knew him not, but as many as received him, he gave power to become the Sons of God; and he that hath the Son, hath Life, he that hath not the
<pb n="5" facs="tcp:61620:3"/>Son, hath not Life, and this life is the light of men; he was in the world and the world was made by him, and the world became fleſh, and dwelt amongſt us, and we ſaw the only begotten Son of God full of Glory, Mercy, Grace, and Peace, and to him that is at reſt, (ſaith Chriſt) will I give of the water of life freely; he that hath an eare may hear what the Spirit ſaith, he that overcomes ſhall reign with me ſaith Chriſt.</hi> Therefore all people take warning berime, and do not deceive your ſelves by a pro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>feſſion of God and Chriſt in words, and have not the life and power of what you profeſs; for it is not profeſſion with<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>out poſſeſſion, that will ſtand you inſtead in the day of the Lord God, which is coming upon all the ungodly of the world; who are out of the life and power, of that which the Scriptures were given forth from, for except a man be born again he cannot ſee the kingdome of God; this Birth is not by mans will, but by the will of God; and where this Birth is known, and witneſſed in the leaſt meaſure, it is hated and perſecuted by the world, as ever it was in the dayes of the Apoſtles and Chriſt; <hi>for if they perſecuted me ſaith Chriſt, they will alſo perſecute you; and if they have done this to the maſter of the houſe, how much more to them of his houſhold?</hi> for the Scribes and Phariſees knew where Chriſt ſhould be born, but when he came they put him to death. The ſame is now made manifeſt, as ever was in the Apoſtles dayes, and in Chriſts time, by the Rulers and Magiſtrates of <hi>New-England,</hi> moſt of all the Rulers and Magiſtrates of the Town of <hi>Boſton</hi> in <hi>New-England,</hi> who have made a law in their own wills to baniſh any, whom they call in ſcorn curſed <hi>Qua<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>kers,</hi> whom the Lord ſends amongſt them, to warn them to turn from the evil of their doings, who witneſs, <hi>Chriſt made manifeſt in them the hope of Glory,</hi> and after they have bani<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſhed them upon pain of death, not to come again into their Town or Juriſdiction, by their Law made in their own wills, when they in obedience to the Lord God of Heaven and Earth, as they were commanded of him to come again, not in con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tempt of their Law, though made in their own wills, but in obedience to the Lord, knowing it was better to obey God than man; thy unchriſtian like have put them to death, and
<pb n="6" facs="tcp:61620:4"/>this is the fruits of <hi>New-Englands</hi> profeſſion, who are out of the life of what they profeſs in words, as their fruits have made them manifeſt, who have put the Innocent to death, who came to bear witneſs to the truth as it is in Jeſus, and as it was made manifeſt in them; but happy I ſay were they who loved not their lives more than Chriſt, who have laid it down for his names ſake, they ſhall receive a good reward, When they that cauſed them to be put to death, ſhall howl and lament; for their day of ſorrow is coming on, for the Innocent blood cryes aloud for vengeance, upon them who put them to death, good it had been for them they had never been born, or that a mil<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtone had been hanged about their neck, and that caſt into the Sea, rather than they ſhould have put them to death; there<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fore all people, who have not had a hand in this thing, in put<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ting the Innocent to death, who have not ſuffered as evill doers, but becauſe they could not be ſubject to the Lawes of men, for conſcience ſake, knowing it better to obey God than men: take warning I ſay betime, <hi>while it is called to day, if you will hear his voice, harden not your hearts, as in a day of Slaugh<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ter,</hi> for verily the day of the Lord God is at hand, wherein all the proud, and they that do wickedly ſhall be deſtroyed: <hi>The axe is laid to the root of the tree, and every tree that bringeth not forth good fruit, muſt be hewen down, and caſt into the fire.</hi> The Lord hath ſaid it, and he will bring it to paſs in this the the day of his mighty Power; for now is the Lord calling by his meſſengers to all the inhabitants of the earth, to come to repentance, repentance from dead works, to ſerve the Lord in newneſſe of life, in holyneſſe and purity, without which none can ſee the Lord; for holineſſe becomes the houſe of God, whoſe houſe we are, whom he hath called out of the world to be a witneſſe to his truth, as it is manifeſt in us, as he hath ſaid, <hi>I will dwell in them, and walk in them, and they ſhall be my people, and I will be their God, faith the Lord,</hi> who is now riſen, and ariſing to redeem a people to himſelf, zealous of good works wrought in Chriſt Jeſus, made manifeſt within, the hope of Glory, and Glory be to the Lord God for ever more, who hath redeemed many to himſelf out of the fallen eſtate, <hi>Adams</hi> State, by Chriſt Jeſus the Second <hi>Adam,</hi> the <pb n="7" facs="tcp:61620:4"/>Lord from Heaven, <hi>for as is the earthly, ſuch are they that are earthly; &amp; as is the heavenly, ſuch are they that are heavenly; for the firſt man</hi> Adam <hi>is of the earth, the ſecond the Lord from Hea<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ven,</hi> and by this Chriſt we witneſſe redemption from ſin, the ſame Chriſt that died at <hi>Jeruſalem</hi> for our ſins, and roſe again for our juſtification, this we can truly ſay indeed and in truth, <hi>that Chriſt is riſen indeed,</hi> and become the firſt fruits of them that ſleep, and by this Chriſt we witneſs re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>demption from ſin, and alſo the Law of the members that warrs againſt the Law of the minde that <hi>Paul</hi> ſpoke of, yet we with <hi>Paul</hi> can ſay, <hi>we thank God through Chriſt Jeſus our Lord, who gives victory, over the law of ſin and death, which the Law could not do in that it was weak through the fleſh. God ſent his Son born of a woman to condemn Sin in the fleſh, that we through him might have life, who believe on him, whom the Father hath ſent into the world, whom the world cannot receive; for he that receiveth me</hi> ſaith Chriſt,
<hi>receiv<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>eth him that ſent me, and he that receiveth you,</hi> ſaith Chriſt to his diſciples, <hi>receiveth me alſo, and he that keeps my ſayings will keep yours alſo: He that hath an ear may hear what the Spirit ſaith, and he that is a thirſt may come and drink freely without mony, or without price;</hi> Oh! dear people, <hi>why do you ſpend your mony for that which is not bread, and your labour for that which doth not ſatisfy?</hi> all you who have been learning may be ſome tenn years, ſome twenty years, ſome thirty years, ſome forty years, ſome fifty years, ſome ſixty years, following the blind guides of the world, and yet not come to the knowledge of truth; but ſome ſay, loe here in this form, and ſome ſay in another; but I ſay believe them not, for where Chriſt is made manifeſt, he is made manifeſt within to de<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtroy the works of the Devil. Now people, ſin is a work of the Devil, and the Devil was a lyar from the beginning, he abode not in the truth; now he that commits ſin abides not in the truth, for Chriſt is the truth, the way and the life; no man can come to the Father but by him: now as none can come to the Father but by Chriſt, ſo none can come to Chriſt but by the light they be enlightned withal, which ſhewes ſin and evill: now all who live in ſin, and hate the light, which ye <pb n="8" facs="tcp:61620:5"/>be enlightned withal, <hi>they will not bring their deeds to the light leſt they ſhould be reproved:</hi> ſo they that hate the light, <hi>and will not come to Chriſt that they might have life,</hi> but goes on in the wicked wayes of the world, in ſcorning &amp; diriſion of their fellow Creatures, who love the light, and are guided by it, and are come to Chriſt, the way, the truth, and the life, who never perſecuted any, neither taught he any ſuch doctrine, as to impriſon any, or whip, or ſtock, or baniſh, or put to death for conſcience ſake, as the Rulers of
<hi>New-England</hi> have done, who cannot receive ſtrangers, but perſecute them, who come to beare witneſſe to the truth, as it is in Jeſus made manifeſt in them the hope of Glory: but here in <hi>New-England</hi> it is made manifeſt, as it was by <hi>Herod,</hi> when Chriſt was born, he ſought to worſhip him, under pretence to deſtroy him; ſo here they call themſelves a Church of Chriſt, but where he is made manifeſt in his members, they put him to death, and caſts them into priſon that comes to live among them, only becauſe they are tituled <hi>Quakers;</hi> and thus they have entertained their country men and friends in <hi>New-England,</hi> and eſpecially at the town of <hi>Boſton,</hi> where they can<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>not endure to ſee one walk in the ſtreet, who they in ſcorn call curſed
<hi>Quakers,</hi> though truly the people in ſcorn called curſed
<hi>Quakers</hi> by them, are they who truly fear the Lord God of Heaven and Earth, and are witneſſes for him againſt the man of ſin, againſt the Beaſt and the falſe Prophet, which they worſhip here in
<hi>New-England</hi> much, moſt of all at this Town of <hi>Boſton:</hi> for all that will not worſhip in their way, though a falſe worſhip, they muſt be baniſhed out of their Town and their Juriſdiction; and if they come again, put them to death. And their fruits have made them manifeſt, to be no Church of Chriſt, but of Anti-chriſt, hypocrites, got above the Light of Chriſt in themſelves, painted Sepulchers, having got the Saints words declared from the life, but are found perſecuting the ſame life, where it is made manifeſt as they were in, that they gave forth the Scripture; truly they are like the ſeaven lean kine of <hi>Egypt,</hi> which eat up the wel-favoured kine, and behold they wear ſtill ill-favoured; ſo they as much as in them lyes, they devour all the appea<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rance <pb n="9" facs="tcp:61620:5"/>of that which is good in any, and yet they remain wicked ſtill, ſo the Scripture comes to be fulfilled of them, <hi>evil men &amp; ſeducers ſhall wax worſe and worſe, deceiving and being deceived;</hi> but truly their condemnation ſlumbers not, for the Lord is coming near to Judgement to reckon with them for their Stew<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ardſhip; for they have been long perſecuting, and now they have put to death, its like they have long thirſted after blood, as their fruits have made it manifeſt indeed to be no Church of Chriſt as they call themſelves, but ſuch as the <hi>cheif Rulers</hi> and
<hi>Prieſts</hi> were of, who put Chriſt to death, who ſaid, <hi>they had a Law, and by their Law he ought to die;</hi> ſo here we have a law ſaid they, if they come here again we will put them to death, they are afraid their kingdom ſhould fall, for it ſhakes already; for they think either now or never when their king<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dom of ſin, which they ſo much plead for, comes to be oppo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſed, and the <hi>Prieſts</hi> trade called in queſtion, who have got ſo much a year by the Scripture, telling the people of other mens conditions, things made ready to their hands, and plead<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing for ſin, it plainly appears that they are Satans meſſengers indeed, who plead for ſin, and ſay men ſhall never be per<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fect while they are here, and yet they muſt have ſo much a year for preaching the <hi>Word of God,</hi> (as they ſay) when the
<hi>Word</hi> is not to be bought and ſold for money; but he that wills
<hi>may buy without money, or without price,</hi> as the Prophet of old have ſaid, <hi>he that thirſts let him come, and he that will may come, and buy wine and milk without money, or without price, and the Word nigh in thee in thy mouth and heart;</hi> the word of faith which <hi>Paul</hi> preached. So people, this is not a chapter or a verſe in Scripture, other mens conditions; but this is a meaſure of the Spirit of Truth, which the Lord foretold by the prophet of old, ſaith he, <hi>It ſhall come to paſſe in the latter days that I will poure out my Spirit upon all fleſh, and your Sons and Daughters ſhall propheſy;</hi> and now is the Lord fulfilling his promiſe, <hi>and his Sons and Daughters doth propheſy;</hi> whereby the world be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>gins to rage, when they ſee the kingdom of Antichriſt is like to fall, and the
<hi>Merchants</hi> of <hi>Babylon,</hi> their wave will not paſſe for currant as formerly it hath done, therefore they have com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bined together againſt the Lord, and againſt his people, <pb n="10" facs="tcp:61620:6"/>whom they in ſcorn call curſed <hi>Quakers,</hi> and have made a law in their will
<hi>to put them to death;</hi> therefore all people who de<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſires after the Lord God of Heaven and Earth, and hopes for mercy and forgiveneſſe for your ſins, (as you will ſay) by Jeſus Chriſt, to ſuch I ſay own the Light of Jeſus Chriſt, which you be enlightned withal, which ſhews ſin and evill, which lets you ſee when you have done wrong, that condemns you for ſo doing, it will let you ſee all that ever you have done in your life time, if you take heed to it to be guided by it, and the ſame Light being minded and obeyed, it will bring you to hear Chriſts voice, <hi>for his ſheep hear his voice and they follow him, but the voice of a tranger they will not follow, and he that hears the voice of the Son of God ſhall live, For the life that I now live</hi> (<hi>ſaid</hi> Paul) <hi>is by the faith of the Son of God in me,</hi> and the ſame life is now made maniteſt in theſe our dayes, as was in the Apoſtles time, and Chriſts time, who ſaid, <hi>He would ſend the Comforter the Spirit of Truth, which ſhould lead into all Truth.</hi> Now this people is not a chapter or verſe in Scripture, other mens conditions, for this is no profit for me, or for another, what other men enjoyed, except I come to enjoy the ſame as they did, who ſpoke forth the Scrip<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ture: ſo people it is not for men and women, to take the Scriptures, or get words out of the Scriptures, and ſay, Thus ſaith the Lord, and this is the Word of God, becauſe they find it written in the Scripture; this was other mens works, the Lord ſaid ſo to them; But wait in the Light of Chriſt within our ſelves, to know the Word there, as they did, who gave forth the Scriptures, and as <hi>David</hi> ſaid, <hi>hark what the Lord ſaith, for he it is that ſpeaks peace to his people, and to the Saints upon earth, that they turn not again to folly, and you may read in the Scripture, that</hi> Paul <hi>ſaid to</hi> Timothy, <hi>thou ha known the Holy Scriptures which was able to make him wiſe unto ſalvation, through faith which is in Chriſt Jeſus, the ſecond of</hi> Timothy <hi>the</hi>
3. <hi>Chap. and 15th verſe.</hi> So all people that deſires to know the truth as it is in <hi>Jeſus,</hi> you muſt come to that of God in your ſelves, and know the Scriptures there, from that which is holy of God in you, as <hi>Paul</hi> ſaid to <hi>Timothy, that which</hi> (is or) <hi>may be known of God <pb n="11" facs="tcp:61620:6"/>is manifeſt within,</hi> as it is ſaid,
<hi>I have ſhewn it to thee O man, what I would have thee to do, to chuſe the good and hate the evil:</hi> So people, be not deceived, God will not be mocked; for ſuch as you ſow, ſuch ſhall you reap; <hi>He that ſows to the fleſh, ſhall of the fleſh reap corrvption, but he that ſows to the Spirit, ſhall reap life eternal,</hi> and this life is in the Son of God, and where he is revealed and made manifeſt, he is revealed within as
<hi>Paul</hi> ſaid, <hi>it pleaſed the Lord to reveal his Son in me,</hi> and where he is now revealed as ever he was, he ſets free from ſin, <hi>for if the Son ſhall make you free, then ſhall you be free indeed.</hi> So people this makes it plainly appear, that they that plead ſo much for ſin, they plead for the Devil, for all ſin is of the Devil, &amp; alſo it appears plainly, that they know not the Son of God that ſets free, who pleads ſo much for ſin, (as the Teachers of the world do) though they can talke much of him by hear-ſay what other men ſpeak, who witneſſed him made manifeſt in them, for the Teachers of the world can ſay as the Prophets ſaid, and as Chriſt ſpoke, and the Apoſtles ſpoke, as they find it written in the Scripture; <hi>and thus ſaith the Lord ſay they,</hi> and may be they will begin to reckon up <hi>Davids</hi> failings, (as thay ſay) and <hi>Peters</hi> denying of Chriſt and ſuch like, and ſo begin to plead for ſin, a thing truly abhorred of all them that fear the Lord, they dare not plead for ſin becauſe God hath forbiden it, ſo the Teachers of the world are out of the true Prophets life that they ſpoke from, who were ſent to warn people <hi>to turn from the evill of their doings;</hi> and Chriſt ſaid to his, <hi>as I am, ſo are you in this preſent world;</hi> and I hope none will ſay Chriſt was a ſinner, for if any ſay, or think ſo they are lyars, and knows not the truth, as it is in Jeſus; and the Apoſtles exhorted them who were turned from dark<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>neſſe to light, <hi>To be perfect, and as many as were perfect be thus minded;</hi> and the Apoſtles was ſent <hi>to turn people from the power of Satan unto God;</hi> and that was and is out of ſin, for ſin is of the Devil: ſo here the Teachers of the world, who have ſo much a year for preaching as they can get more or leſſe at ſuch a Town, or ſuch a Pariſh as they call it, on ſuch and ſuch dayes, and may be ſome preach by a glaſſe a hour
<pb n="12" facs="tcp:61620:7"/>or more as their ſermon holds out: ſo here they are limited to a time, and place contrary to the Apoſtles, who were to go into all Nations to Preach, and they were not to have ſo much a year where ever they came, neither bargained before hand; neither taught any for filthy lucre, as the Teachers of the world do, that people ſhould never be free from ſin, while they were upon the earth, for the Saints of old were ſet free from ſin <gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="4 letters">
                  <desc>••••</desc>
               </gap>e they were upon earth, and the ſame is now made manifeſt as ever was in the Apoſtles days; Glory and Honor, be given to God for evermore, and the Lamb of God is now riſen and ariſing, <hi>who makes warr in Righteouſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>neſſe, who is ſaving his people from their ſins,</hi> who is giving them victory dayle, who now follow him in the regenera<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tion or new birth, <hi>which is not born by mans will, but by the will of God,</hi> which is heir of the kingdom, which never fades away. So all people deceive not your ſelves
<gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="1 word">
                  <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
               </gap> pro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>feſſion of God and Chriſt, which you have or may not in words, and have not the life, which the words were given forth from, and ceaſe from your <hi>hireling Shepherds,</hi> and <hi>Teach<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ers,</hi> who preach peace to all for mony, if you put into their mouths; <hi>but if you put not into their mouths, they will prepare warr againſt you,</hi> and may be rayle much upon you, as they have againſt others before; if you will not buy their ſtuff at their rate, they will ſay you are deluded and bewitched; when any comes to beare witneſſe againſt their falſe worſhip, which they have ſet up, to compel all to bow down to their God, though a falſe God: Now <hi>Chriſt</hi> and his
<hi>Diſciples,</hi> whom he ſent forth, they never taught any ſuch doctrine, that all that would not come and hear them, might be baniſhed or put in priſon, till they acknowledge their fault as they call it, in not coming to their worſhip, or elſe pay ſuch a ſum of mony a week, as their Rulers and Prieſts of <hi>Boton</hi> in <hi>New-England</hi> do, who hath put men to death for conſcience ſake, becauſe they cannot obey their wicked law made in their own wills; and this is the fruits of
<hi>New-Englands</hi> pro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>feſſion, burning men, as ſome men uſe to do with their ox<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>en in the horns, that they might know them from others, and
<pb n="13" facs="tcp:61620:7"/>cutting mens ears, as men mark their cattel to know them by, and baniſhing of people, and putting them to death, and beating them with pitch ropes even to death, and whiping of them that fear the Lord God of Heaven and Earth, who are moved of him to come thouſands of miles, to bear witneſs to his truth, <hi>whiping</hi> of them, and <hi>baniſhing</hi> of them, and putting of them to death, and caſting them into priſon, that come to inhabit among them; all this is accounted but a ſmall thing in
<hi>New-England,</hi> moſt of all at the town of <hi>Boſton,</hi> where they call themſelves a Church of Chriſt; but let all people that fear the Lord, or deſire to know the truth, as it is in Jeſus, Judge what a Church this is, who neither fears God, nor reverences man, that hath dealt thus with their fellow-creatures, who have been moved of the Lord to come from far, to warn them of the evil of their doings; this is a bad requital indeed, to requite the Lord evil for good, who hath thus dealt with his ſervants, whom he hath ſent among them, to exhort them <hi>to turne from the evil of her doings,</hi> and yet theſe <hi>Rulers,</hi> and <hi>Magiſtrates,</hi> and
<hi>Prieſts,</hi> will plead for ſin, and deal thus with them, that would admoniſh them to turn from it, <hi>this is a filthy, and a horrible thing indeed, that is com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mitted in this land, Prophets propheſy falſly, and the Prieſts bear rule by their means, and people love to have it ſo, and what will you do in the end thereof: Oh dear people conſider betime while it is called to day, if you will hear his voice harden not your hearts againſt the Lord, leaſt he vex you in his wrath, and trouble you in his hote diſpleaſure, which is coming on.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>
               <hi>Some may object and ſay, at what time ſoever a ſinner doth re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pent, the Lord will forgive.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>To which I anſwer, at what time ſoever a ſinner doth truly repent, and turn from the evill of his doings, he ſhall find mercy with the Lord, who is worthy to be feared: But let none dare to continue in ſin, and ſay, at what time ſoever a ſinner doth repent, he ſhall find mercy,
<hi>but while it is called to day, if you will come to true repentance from dead works, to ſerve the living God in newneſſe of life,</hi> owne the light of Chriſt in you, which ſhewes ſin, and evil, in will bring you out of <pb n="14" facs="tcp:61620:8"/>the worlds ways, and cuſtoms, and faſhions, and traditions of men, that you have long lived in, if you take heed to it to be guided by it, you will come to Chriſt to feel him <hi>in you the hope of Glory, he who ſaves his people from their ſins, he who is the Power of God unto ſalvation, to all them that believe in him,</hi> who own his light, and take heed to that to be guided by it, <hi>until the day dawn, and the day-ſtar ariſe in their hearts, for you have an unction which is holy, and you need not that any man teach you, but as the anoynting teacheth;</hi> but firſt you muſt come to the light, to take heed to that, to be guided by that <hi>till the day dawn, and the day ſtar ariſe in your hearts,</hi> and then you will come to know the anoynting <hi>which teacheth all things, which is truth, and no lye.</hi> But people take heed of the worlds words, which they think is repentance, when they have done evill, as lying, or ſwearing, or being drunk, or ſtolne, or other ſin whatſoever they will ſay, when ſome thing within them condemns them for it, God forgive me; but O! that will not ſerve people, when a man or woman hath done wrong, and ſinned againſt God, and in the ſame na<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ture that they committed the offence againſt God, ſay God forgive me, for thats a taking Gods name in vain; for God hears not ſinners until they come to that of God in them, that ſhews ſin and evil, to be guided by that, that ſo they may be led out of ſin; for all their praying, and reading, and hearing, in the firſt nature is abomination to God, he hears not that, it is but <hi>Cains</hi> Sacrifice, which God did not accept; but <hi>Abells</hi> the righteous, God did accept; So it is the ſe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cond birth, the Righteous that God hears, that which is immortal of himſelf, that which he hath given to e<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>very man to profit withal, a meaſure of himſelf, which is Gods gift to man, to bring man again to God, from whence he is fallen: In <hi>Adams</hi> State, the natural man knows not the things of God, they are ſpiritually diſcerned; ſo people it is not ſaying, when you have done evil, God forgive me, in that nature wherein you have committed the offence, but if you hope for mercy, and forgiveneſſe of your ſins (as you will ſay) by Jeſus Chriſt, you muſt come to that of God in
<pb n="15" facs="tcp:61620:8"/>you, that ſhews you ſin, and evil, and tells you you ſhould not have done ſo; now if you turne to that which ſhewes you ſin and evill in your ſelves, to take heed to it to be guided by it, it will lead you out of ſin in a contrary way to the world, and the vanities thereof, and from the hireling <hi>Shepherds,</hi> and <hi>Teachers</hi> of the world, for he that is is a friend to the world, is in the enmity againſt God, and thats out of the truth, <hi>for God is Truth, and with him is no variableneſs nor turning at all, for he waits to be gracious to all them who deſires to turn from the evil of their do<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ings, that ſo they may find mercy with him, whoſe mercy is to be had in remembrance al the day long, ſo he that hath an ear let him hear:</hi> And ſo forſake his ſin, and own the light of Chriſt Jeſus, which you be enlightned withal, it will bring you, if you take heed to it to be guided by it from the hirelings, <hi>the greedy dum dogs that ſeeks for their gain from their quarters:</hi> ſo if you come to the light of Chriſt in you, to be guided by that, you will come to know the teachings of God in Spirit, <hi>for the Children of God are taught of God,</hi> and they are eſtabliſhed in righteouſneſs, and they are far from oppreſſion: the juſt is at liberty, the witneſſe of God within, that which teſtifies againſt ſin: So all people come to the light of Chriſt in you, that ſo you may come out of bondage, for the bond-womans ſon, muſt not be heir with the ſon of the free woman, bondman muſt be caſt out, that which keeps the ſeed in bondage <hi>Iſmael</hi>-like, which is wild, and heady, and angry, and raſh, and froward, that genders unto-ſtrife, and every evill work, and workers of iniquity muſt be deſtroyed; ſo to that which is pure of God in you, turn your minds, and wait in that, that ſo you may come to know Gods worſhip, <hi>which is in Spirit and in Truth;</hi> for now is he ſeeking ſuch worſhipers, and many are come to know his worſhip, but this worſhip is not at a houſe made with hands, as <hi>Steven</hi> was ſtoned to death, for bearing wittneſſe againſt temples made with hands,
<hi>Acts</hi> the 7th chap. and the 48. verſe, but the worſhip of God is within, its known there, and he is worſhiped within, in the meaſure of his own ſpirit; So all you that hunger and thirſt after right couſneſſe, come to the Light, that ſo you may come to know and worſhip God in
<pb n="16" facs="tcp:61620:9"/>Spirit and in Truth, that you may come to know <hi>the Law written in your hearts, and Spirit in your inward parts,</hi> to obey the Lord God of Heaven and Earth, there to worſhip him. That ſo you may come to know the teaching of the Lord by his Spirit, as the children of the Lord do; That ſo you may come to know the Scriptures fulfilled in you, as they did who ſpoke them forth; That ſo you may ſay, the Scriptures is yours indeed, and Truth; And when you are come to know theſe things in your ſelves, you will know Chriſt to be a Savi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>our to you, <hi>ſaving you from ſin;</hi> For this know aſſuredly, that if you come not to know Chriſt within you, a Saviour to ſave you from ſin, then you are reprobates indeed, from the Faith which is in Chriſt Jeſus our Lord and Saviour; to whom be Glory, and Honor, and Prayſe, for ever and ever, <hi>Amen.</hi>
            </p>
         </div>
         <div type="tract">
            <pb n="17" facs="tcp:61620:9"/>
            <head>To all you Rulers, and Magiſtrates, and Prieſts in
<hi>New-England,</hi> moſt of all of the Town of <hi>Boſton</hi> in
<hi>New-England,</hi> who have put the ſervants of the Living God to death: Whereas you ſay in your Law, there is a curſed Sect of Here<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ticks riſen up in the World, which are com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>monly called <hi>Quakers,</hi> who take upon them to be immediately ſent of God, and infal<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>libly aſſiſted by the Spirit, to ſpeak and write Blaſpemous Opinions, deſpiſing Go<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vernment, and the Order of God in Church and Common-wealth, ſpeaking evil of Dig<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nities, reproaching and reviling Magi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtrates and Miniſters, ſeeking to turn the People from the Faith, and Gain Proſelites to their pernitious wayes.</head>
            <p>THE People in ſcorn and deriſion called <hi>Quakers</hi> by you, are they who truly fear the Lord God of Hea<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ven, and who in obedience to his Command, by his Spi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rit have been moved of him to come amongſt you, to de<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>clare the Word of Truth as, it is manifeſt in Jeſus, whom you have evil entreated, you have whipped many, and cut of the ears of ſome, as men uſe to mark their baeſts, you have <pb n="18" facs="tcp:61620:10"/>burnt ſome, as men uſe to do their Oxen in the Horns, that they might know them from others, and you have baniſh<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ed ſome, and you have caſt many into Priſon without the breach of any Juſt Law, even them that were your Inhabi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tants; and alſo them that have come from far to live a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mongſt you, and you have unchriſtian-like put ſome to death, having no juſt cauſe againſt any of them, but that you have hatched miſchief out of Hell, and in your wills have made a Law to puniſh the innocent, by whom the Lord ſends amongſt you to warn you, to turn from the evil of your doings; and thus you have requited the Lord evil for all his good to you ward; and you do deſpite againſt the Spirit of Grace for the People called Hereticks and curſed
<hi>Quakers</hi> by you, who take upon them, as you ſay, to be immediately ſent of God, and infallibly aſſiſted by the Spirit; this we own and witneſs to be true in our meaſures to be immediately ſent of God, and to be guided by his Spirit, that's of God; but to write or ſpeak blaſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>phemous opinions, that we do deny, that hath not been proved againſt us yet by any of you or your hireling Prieſts; for they who are guided by the Spirit of God, they neither ſpeak nor write blaſpemous opinions, for the Spirit of God is not a ſpirit of blaſpemy, as you may think or judge it to be, who make a mock at an immediate Call; and you are the Hereticks, who are gone from that of God in you, who are erred from the Spirit as <hi>Balaam</hi> was, who loved the wages of unrighteouſneſs, as you Teachers do; and the People by you in ſcorn called <hi>Quakers,</hi> are not curſed, but bleſſed of the Lord, who came amongſt you to bear witneſs for the truth as it is in Jeſus; for although you have uſed incliantment as <hi>Balaak</hi> and <hi>Balaam</hi> did together to curſe <hi>Jacob</hi> and defie <hi>Iſrael,</hi> yet your Inchantments and Laws, which you have hatched out of Hell ſhall be broken, and you both and the people in ſcorn by you called curſed <hi>Quakers,</hi> ſhall inhabit amongſt you, and you ſhall be bro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ken to pieces, the Lord hath ſaid it, and he will ſhortly bring it to paſs, you cannot long ſtrive againſt God and proſper, <pb n="19" facs="tcp:61620:10"/>for he is riſen againſt you already; and though your trum<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pets ſound aloud amongſt you, who delight to ſhed inno<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cent blood; yet the Trumpet of the Lord ſound, louder in his ears, which cryes aloud for vengeance againſt you, who have put his ſervant to death, your condemnation is coming on apace, you are all to be condemned with the light that comes from Jeſus Chriſt the Son of God,
<hi>who lighteth every man that comes into the World.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>And whereas you ſay, We deſpiſe Government, and Order in Church &amp; Commonwealth, ſpeaking evil of Dig<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nities, reproach Magiſtrates and Miniſters; that's falſe, for we own Government and Miniſters, who fear the Lord, hates covetouſneſs, and are guided by the Spirit of the Lord; but if any Magiſtrates makes Laws contrary to truth, as you have done, to put the innocent to death, we utterly deny both the Laws and Magiſtrates therein; but Magiſtrates, who are a terrour to evil-doers, and a praiſe to them that do well, we own; but ſuch Magiſtrates are not you, who ſhed innocent blood; and we own ſuch Miniſters as are cal<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>led of God,
<hi>Who are ſent out to preach the Goſpel freely without money, or without price;</hi> but ſuch Miniſters are not your Hire<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lings, who can never have enough, who would limit the Spirit of God in others, who would have none to ſpeak but themſelves, that ſo they might keep people ſtill in igno<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rance, as they have done, ever learning, and never able to come to the knowledge of the truth; but you Magiſtrates and Miniſters ſo called, are all made manifeſt as <hi>Corah, Da<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>than</hi> and <hi>Abiram</hi> was, who rebelled againſt <hi>Moſes,</hi> who ſaid, <hi>All the Congregation were Holy:</hi> but your end will be like theirs, for your Cup is almoſt full of which you muſt drink, doubtleſs it ſhall be filled to you, your reward you ſhall have, for God will be honoured by you, but it will be your de<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtruction you generation of vipers, of ſerpents, who gnaſh your teeth for torment already, for your torment is begun already, your ſorrow ſhall never ceaſe nor flye away, your deſtruction draws near, you cannot eſcape the hand of the Almighty, he riſes againſt you, he will render vengeance in
<pb n="20" facs="tcp:61620:11"/>flames of f<gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="5 letters">
                  <desc>•••••</desc>
               </gap>on you, wo be unto you who had no pitty, <hi>good it had been for you if you had not been born,</hi> on that <hi>a Mil-ſtone had been hanged about your neck, and you caſt into the Sea,</hi> rather than you ſhould have made a wicked Law; and ſo put the innocent to death, as you have done, whoſe innocent blood cryes aloud for vengeance againſt you inhabitants of this Town of <hi>Boſton</hi> in <hi>New-England,</hi> who have ſhed innocent blood; Gods Judgments draws near all you, who had a hand in ſhedding innocent blood, the blood of the innocent is upon you, wo will be to you for evermore except you repent, you are grown fat and ſtrong, and you ſpurn with the heel againſt God; you are worſe than <hi>Pharaoh</hi> was, who ſaid, <hi>Who was the Lord, that he ſhould obey him to let Iſrael go;</hi> wo will be to you for ever, who will not let the Lords people worſhip him in his own way, but they muſt be caſt into Priſon, and whipt, and baniſhed, and their ears cut, and burnt, and put to death, becauſe they come to bear witneſs to the truth a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>gainſt your Idolatrous worſhip, and witneſs the true wor<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſhip, who worſhip him in Spirit and in Truth: And now is he ſeeking ſuch worſhippers, but you have rejected his meſſengers, and ſlighted the day of your viſitation, and put his ſervants to death, and evil intreated many, whom he hath ſent amongſt you to bear witneſs to his truth as it is manifeſt in Jeſus, but ſorrow ſhall accompany you, where ever you go vengeance from the Lord and puniſh<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ment as came upon <hi>Cain</hi> ſhall come upon you, curſed ſhall you be for evermore, in ſorrow ſhall you lye down, and ſo ſhall you riſe up, and in torment ſhall you be where ever ye go, your God whom you ſerve is not able to deliver you out my hand ſaith the Lord, your prayers and praiſes are accurſed of God, your ſacrifices is
<hi>Cain</hi>-like, God will ne<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ver hear you, your bud ſhall rot as the drunkard, for you are drunk with the Saints words, and you ſhall have blood to drink who have ſhed innocent blood; and this is to you who have put the ſervants of the Living God to Death.</p>
            <pb n="21" facs="tcp:61620:11"/>
            <p>TO you the Inhabitants of <hi>Boſton</hi> in
<hi>New-England,</hi> who have not had a hand in putting the innocent to death, if <hi>ye will return, return unto me</hi> ſaith the Lord, or elſe I will viſit your ſin upon you with the reſt, <hi>for when I begin, I will alſo make an end;</hi> therefore if ye will return unto me ſaith the Lord, I will yet have mercy upon your unrighteouſneſs, if you will break off your ſins by true re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pentance, and own the light of Chriſt Jeſus which you be enlightned withal, which ſhews you your tranſgreſſions, which lets you ſee when you have done any manner of thing that is evil, which reproves you in ſecret when no eye ſees you, for whatſoever is done in ſecret ſhall be made ma<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nifeſt by the light, for the day is dawning, and the ſun-ri<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſing is appearing amongſt you, and wo will be unto all you, who cover your ſelves, and not with the Spirit of the Lord, for he will find you all out, your ſecret works of darkneſs muſt now be brought to light, your covers will be too narrow, all you who are covered but not with the Spirit of the Lord, your covers muſt all be rent off, root and branch muſt be deſtroyed and burnt up of all you, who are covered but not with the Spirit of our God, who is a con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſuming fire to all his enemies, who waits to be gratious to all you, who have any deſires to turn from the evil of your doings, that ſo you may find mercy with the Lord, that you may be hid in the day of the Lords fierce wrath, that ſo you may not periſh with the rebellions and ſtiff-necked, and uncircumciſed Rulers and Magiſtrates, and Prieſts and People, who have had a hand in putting the innocent to death, amongſt you, who have not ſuffered as evil-doers, but for righteouſneſs ſake, becauſe they could not be ſubject to their wicked Law, made contrary to the truth; To you I ſay, to you I ſpeak, who have not had a hand in ſhed<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ding innocent blood; Be ye all warned betime, <hi>while it is called to day, if you will hear his voice, harden not your hearts againſt the Lord;</hi> for verily I ſay unto you, except <pb n="22" facs="tcp:61620:12"/>
               <hi>you repent, you ſhall all periſh,</hi> as they who have put the innocent to death, for all your Meeting together, and Prayers, and ſinging and praiſing God as you think, is abomination in the ſight of God, he never hears you, it is but a ſacrifice offered in the firſt nature, which God never accepts in any, for the prayers of an ungenerate man God hears not, as you may read in Scripture; its the ſecond birth God hears, as <hi>Abel</hi> was, the Righteous, whom <hi>Cain</hi> the murtherer ſlew, his ſacrifices God did not accept, but <hi>Abels</hi> he had reſpect to: ſo until you come to be guided by that of God in you which is immortal, which gave forth the Scriptures, God hears not your Prayers, though there may be a Seal, yet it is not according to truth, for Chriſt is the truth, and where Chriſt is known, he redeems again to the Father, and ſo the loſt eſtate comes to be recovered again in him, ſo the immortal of God is known. and wit<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>neſſed in and through Jeſus Chriſt, the ſame as ever was, which died at
<hi>Jeruſalem,</hi> who is now ſaving his people from their ſins; for now the <hi>blind ſee,</hi> the <hi>lame walk,</hi> the <hi>dumb ſpeak,</hi> and <hi>the lepers are cleanſed,</hi> the ſame as ever was, glory be to God for evermore, who is now ſhedding, his ſaving health abroad to all Nations; the Glad Tidings of the Goſpel is now going forth, and preaching Repen<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tance to the Spirits in Priſon; but this Goſpel is not the four books
<hi>Matthew, Mark, Luke</hi> and <hi>John,</hi> as many may think it to be; for
<hi>if the Goſpel be hid, it is hid to them that are lost;</hi> but the four books are not hid, for ma<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ny have got them, but know not the Glad Tidings of the Goſpel, for that's hid to all them who cannot witneſs Redemption by Chriſt Jeſus by their ſins, but are in the old nature, <hi>Adams</hi> ſtate, driven out from God into the earth, groaping in the dark like the blind <hi>Sodomites,</hi> but cannot find the door; for Chriſt is the door,
<hi>He is the good Shepheard the Sheep hear his voice and follow him but the voice of a tranger they will not follow, they will flye from the ſtranger;</hi> they know ſtrangers, who have got the Saints words, but perſecute the Saints life: they are ſtrangers <pb n="23" facs="tcp:61620:12"/>indeed, who would limit the Spirit of God in any; for <hi>Moſes</hi> the man of God ſaid, <hi>He would all the Lords People had been Prophets;</hi> and thouſand in <hi>Old-England,</hi> glory be to God, know the true Shepheard, who feeds with the Bread of Life, from them who feed with the husk, who feed amongſt Swine and Dogs, who rent and tear, and devour their fellow-creatures, who have marred their Re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ligion, and ſhamed their Profeſſion, and ſtained their Na<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tion with blood; but all in <hi>vain do they worſhip God teaching for Doctrine the Precepts of men;</hi> for the Mighty Day of the Lord God of Heaven and Earth is coming upon all them, that obey not the Goſpel of our Lord Jeſus Chriſt, wherein the workers of iniquity muſt be deſtroyed; and all them, who keep the Seed of God in bondage, without which we had been as <hi>Sodom</hi> and <hi>Gomorrah,</hi> which periſhed in one day: And now is the Lord riſen and ariſing for his Seeds ſake, and wo to all them that keep the Seed in bondage, who will not let the oppreſſed go free to ſerve the Lord, and worſhip the Lord in his own way, but will dig up to themſelves broken Ciſterns that can hold no water, and ſo forſake Chriſt the Fountain of living Waters; for he is Antichriſt who denies Chriſt come in the fleſh, and ſuch are they who put him to death in his Members; for if Chriſt be not in you, then are you reprobates indeed from the true Faith, which is in our Lord Jeſus Chriſt. So dear people be not deceived any longer with a Profeſſion of God and Chriſt in words, and be ſtrangers from the life of what you profeſs, for it is <hi>not every one that ſaith Lord, Lord, ſhall enter; but he that doth the Will of God,</hi> he knows the hidden things, which are hid from the Wiſe and Prudent, and revealed unto Babes; ſo all people come down to the light of Chriſt in you, that ſo you may come to the life of what you profeſs in words, that ſo you may come to know the Power, as they did, who gave forth the Words; for they are hypocrites who know not the Life and Power of what they profeſs in words; ſuch are hypo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>crites indeed, got above the light of Chriſt in themſelves,
<pb n="24" facs="tcp:61620:13"/>painted Sepulchers indeed, got the Saints Words to talk of, and perſecute the Saints life, and ſuch know not God and Chriſt, but by hear ſay, what ever they may profeſs in words, yet they know not the life, who perſecute and put to death for Conſcience ſake, and threaten others with the like, who are moved of the Lord to live amongſt them: So he <hi>that hath anear let him hear, and forſake the evil of his doings, and I will have mercy</hi> ſaith the Lord, and <hi>turn to our God, for he will abundantly pardon,</hi> if ye turn unto me ſaith the Lord, by timely Repentance before it be hid from your eyes; for if your Rulers and Prieſts would have heard the truth, they would not have put the innocent to death, but let them now beware, leaſt it be now hid from their eyes.</p>
            <closer>
               <signed>
                  <hi>From a Friend of</hi> Iſrael, <hi>Commonwealth, who here ſuffers for the truth as it is in Jeſus amongſt you Inhabitants of</hi> Boſton <hi>in</hi> New-England, <hi>who cannot bow down to your God, nor your worſhip, becauſe a falſe God and falſe worſhip, but ſtands a witneſs a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>gainſt your falſe worſhip, and wic<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ked law which you have made, even till death: Known to the world by name of</hi> JOSEPH NICHOLSON.</signed>
            </closer>
            <trailer>THE END.</trailer>
            <pb facs="tcp:61620:13"/>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
